Equations pertaining to pv energy generation
--------------------------------------------

1. Equation for energy of photons (A)
	Given: Eph = energy of photon  && Eg = band gap energy
	if Eph < Eg
		photons pass through as if they are transparent
	if Eph = Eg
		photons are efficiently absorbed
	if Eph > Eg
		photons are absorbed STRONGLY, but their strength is not fully harnessed as

2. We Know Solar Rule of Thumb (B)
	a 4 KW system will produce about 5,200 kWh anually. The system is about 228 sq. ft
		*This then assumes that the solar panels are experiencing 1,300 peak hours per year, or 14.84% of the years total hours.
		*How much time is that for the average hours per day? About three and a half hours (3.5616)





Hypothetical Master Equation
----------------------------
A Hypothesis for the grand equation. Each vairable would need extra research, but I can start from here. This master equation will read left to right, starting from the least complicated factors to determine to the most complicated.

It should be noted that this equation calculates the ANNUAL amount of electricity. I can think about smaller spans of time later.

First, I can assume there is a calculable max. amount of energy to be generated from the solar panel:
		Max amount 
			= (Wattage of the system) * Number of hours in the year
			or
		mx = Ws * h/y
			where h/y = 8760 hours when days per year (d/y) = 365 and 
		 	where h/y = 8784 hours when d/y = 366
	
	*This equation is more than ideal, as it assumes not only that the panels will remain fully functional and unobstructed, but also that the sun is shining directly on the panels at all times of the day, even at night. This is done intentionally to simplify the rest of the equation, since all other coefficients will work to scale the amount down to a reasonable prediction of total energy generated.

After finding the max amount of energy, the easiest variable to find would be night hours per year. This is easy because day/nighttime hours can be predicted far in advance, and since no energy is generated at night, these hours can be subtracted from mx cleanly, without the need to factor in the possiblity of suboptimal energy yields. The equation is as follows

      Night hours = (Hours of midnight to dawn) + (Hours of sundown to midnight)
	*dawn and sundown would be vairables, as their times change according to season and location. Midnight in the first coefficient will be 0 because it represents the start of the new day. It will be 12 in the second coefficient becuase it represents the end of the last half of the day.
	h/n = (dwn) + (12 - dsk)
	*I'll figure out how to find 'dwn' and 'dsk' later. That'll probably take external data from weather centers and may need more consideration when I start coding.

The next coefficient considers the amount of sunlight harnessed during the suboptimal hours. This assumes that the skies are clear for all hours of the day. This value would be too hard to determine while writing this, but here is the declaration: S(t) where "dwn <= t <= sdn"


Now the equation must factor in the possibility of obstruction. This will require the following information:
	-Preexisting records of the region's annual weather patterns
	-knowledge of the buildings, trees, and other physical obstructions within the area.
	-the orientation of the solar panels (do they face straight up, on a slanted roof, on a pivot?)
	
	In regards to all three of these questions, I think the answer rests in the amount of light harnessed during their effective time. Of course, this assumes that the obstruction does not influence the energy in the wavelengths. I will have to research this assumption later. It is possible that, even it is false, the change in energy does not have significant impact on how much electricity is being generated. Here are the basic equations for each coefficient
	wthr = S(t) - energy lost because of weather obstructions (weather)
	objct = S(t) - energy lost because of shade (object)
	orntn = S(t) - energy lost becuase the panel wasn't facing the sun (orientation)
	
	*these coefficents may be useful but are not necessarily in the master equation. This is how the variables would be added:
		vars(t) = (Ws - (S(t) - weather(t) - object - orientation))
	*'t' is a part of weather because this, like the hour of daytime, changes with time
	*Ws is subtracted from everything else to show how much energy was lost in that hour 

The above variables must be scaled to fit the measurement of years. This section currently only focuses on one hour in a given day. The subequation must then add together all hours to make a day, then all days to make a year. 
	in a day: Σ(t, dwn to dsk) (vars(t))
	in a year: Σ(day, 1 to d/y) (Σ(t, dwn to dsk) (vars(t)))

There is likely more things that could affect how much electricity is generated, but I do not know if I will have time to investigate every aspect. The following eqation is the master equation that I will be researching and coding:
	
     Total energy = Maximum possible energy - night hours per year - energy missed because of suboptimal conditions

	or

	E = Emax - h/n - Σ(day, 1 to d/y) (Σ(t, dwn to dsk) (vars(t)))
	
	!Pan also wanted me to implement the brand of panels into the equation. I should check to see what it would affect and in what way I can implement it. 
	!(Update 9-13-15) 'object' variable will be heretofore called 'partial shading' or 'ps'. Partial shading is the technical term for objects interfering with a panel's path to sunlight.
	


Sources:
A. pvenergy.org
B. weknowsolar.com/solar-faqs.html
