Notes for the YieldOpt Research 

Key Terms
-tripple junction solar cell: uses three junctions to take in different wavelengths of light.
	*A single junction solar cell has a theoretical max. efficiency of 34%, while a supposed ∞ amount of junctions could yield about 86.8% under concentrated sunlight

-quantum efficiency: amount of carriers collected to the # of photons in an energy incident. Efficiency changes according to wavelength. A 1:1 ratio gives UNITY.

-concentrating photovoltaic modules (CPV): Solar modules using reflection and magnification to increase solar efficiency. While they show promise in taking over future markets, this type of module is rarely used


Basis of Paper:
YieldOpt is an algorithm used to predict PV energy output with a 3% deviation. It is based on an earlier model called Syracuse, but provides in-depth treatment of concentrator optics within the equation.

***Due to infrequent usage of CPV's in the PV market, further reading on CPV's will be postponed for a later time***

